http://www.bankwest.com.au/legal-stuff/bankwest-privacy-policy

Bankwest Privacy Policy
Printable Privacy Policy (PDF)
Bankwest provides a wide range of banking and financial services. This policy describes how your personal information is handled by us.
Bankwest is a division of the Commonwealth Bank of Australia (CBA) which has subsidiaries (the Group) that provide banking, finance, insurance, funds management, financial planning and advice, superannuation, stockbroking and other services. The Group includes Bankwest, CBA, CommSec, CommInsure, Commonwealth Financial Planning and Colonial First State businesses.
Australian members of our Group are bound by the Privacy Act and the Australian Privacy Principles (APPs). CBA has a separate but consistent privacy policy which can be viewed at commbank.com.au.
For more information about the Group, including a complete list of Group members, see the CBA’s latest Annual Report, available at commbank.com.au/shareholders.
In addition to the Privacy Act, individuals located in the European Union (EU) may also have rights under EU based rules known as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).  The GDPR has harmonised the data privacy laws of each individual EU country, giving more rights to individuals located in the EU and more obligations to organisations holding their personal information.
Details of additional rights of individuals located in the EU and how we meet them are outlined in Appendix 1 of the Bankwest Privacy Policy (PDF).
We take privacy seriously and are committed to ensuring the protection of your personal information, no matter where you are located.
We protect your information, and aim to be clear and open about what we do with it. You can find more information in places like our application forms and terms and conditions.
We understand your privacy is important to you, and we value your trust. That’s why we protect your information and aim to be clear about what we do with it.
This Policy explains how we handle your personal information. It also includes:
Our policy on the handling of credit reports and other credit information
Key information about credit reporting matters.
During your relationship with us, we may tell you more about how we handle your information. For example, when you complete an application or claims form, or receive terms and conditions or a Product Disclosure Statement. You should always read these documents carefully.
Sometimes we update our privacy policy. You can always find the most up-to-date version on our website.
We collect information about you when you use our products or services, or deal with us. We may also collect information about you from other people and organisations.
Information we collect from you
We collect personal information about you when you contact us, use our products or services, visit our websites or use our mobile apps or deal with us in some other way.
The information we collect from you may include:
Information about your identity – including your name, address, date of birth, gender and marital status
Your Tax File Number or tax residency status
Health information – for example for insurance purposes
Financial and transaction information
When you visit our websites or use our mobile apps – your location information, IP address and any third-party sites you access. Some of this website information we collect using Cookies. For more information please see the Website Terms of Use
When you access our mobile apps using an Android mobile device – any suspected malware detected on your mobile.
Other personal information, such as details of your interactions with us.
Information we collect from others
We collect information about you from others, such as:
Service providers
Agents
Advisers
Brokers
Employers
Companies or bodies that you own shares in or have an interest in
Family members.
For example, if you apply for credit, we may ask a credit reporting body for your credit report. If you apply for life or income protection insurance, we may ask you or your doctor for your medical information. We may also collect information about you that is publicly available (for example, in public registers or on social media) or provided by businesses we deal with.
Sensitive information
The Privacy Act protects your sensitive information – such as information about your religion, ethnicity, health or biometrics (for example, your fingerprints). If we need this type of information, we will ask for your permission – except where otherwise allowed by law.
We’re careful about how we use your information. We use it to deliver our products and services. We also use your information for other reasons, such as to better understand you and your needs, and to let you know about other products and services you might be interested in.
We collect, use and exchange your information so that we can:
Confirm your identity
Assess your applications for a product or service
Design, manage, price and provide our products and services
Manage our relationship with you
Minimise risks and help identify and investigate fraud and other illegal activities, or the presence of suspected malware on your Android mobile device that might affect your use of our mobile apps
Contact you, for example, when we need to tell you something important
Improve our services to you and your experience with us
Comply with laws, and assist government and law enforcement agencies
Manage our business.
We may also collect, use and exchange your information in other ways where permitted by law.
Bringing you new products and services
From time to time, we may also use your information to tell you about products or services we think you might be interested in. To do this, we may contact you by:
Email
Phone
SMS
Social media
Advertising through our apps, websites, or third-party websites
Mail.
If you don’t want to receive direct marketing messages or want to change your contact preferences, please call 13 17 19.
Using data to give you better customer service
We’re always working to improve our products and services and give you the best customer experience.
New technologies let Group members combine information we have about you and our other customers, for example transaction information, with data from other sources, such as third party websites or the Australian Bureau of Statistics. Our Group members analyse this data to learn more about you and other customers, and how to improve our products and services.
The Group members use this combined data to help other businesses better understand their customers. When we do, we don’t pass on any personal information about you.
We may share your information with other members of the CommBank Group. We may also share your information with others for the reasons mentioned in Section 4.
We may share your information with other members of the Group. This helps us offer you a high-quality customer experience. You can read about how Group members may use your information in Section 4.
We may also share your information with third parties for the reasons in Section 4 or where the law otherwise allows. These third parties can include:
Service providers – for example, mortgage insurers, loyalty program partners and our product distributors
Businesses who do some of our work for us –  including direct marketing, statement production, debt recovery and IT support
Brokers, agents, advisers and persons who act on your behalf – such as your parent (if you are under 16), guardian or a person with Power of Attorney
Guarantors and other security providers
Organisations involved in our funding arrangements – like loan purchasers, investors, advisers, researchers, trustees and rating agencies
People who help us process claims – like assessors and investigators
Other banks and financial institutions – for example, if we need to process a claim for a mistaken payment
Auditors, insurers and re-insurers
Current or previous employers – for example, to confirm your employment
Government and law enforcement agencies or regulators
Credit reporting bodies and credit providers
Organisations that help identify illegal activities and prevent fraud
Other people using the same account, like joint applicants or joint account holders or cardholders.
Sending information overseas
Sometimes, we may send your information overseas, including to:
Overseas businesses that are part of the Group
Service providers or other third parties who store data or operate outside Australia
Complete a transaction, such as an International Money Transfer
Comply with laws, and assist government or law enforcement agencies.
If we do this, we make sure there are arrangements are in place to protect your information. You can find out which countries your information may be sent to at commbank.com.au/security-privacy/country-list.pdf.
If you ask us for credit, we may check your credit reports. We get these from credit reporting bodies. We also share your credit information with them so they can provide credit reports to others.
When you apply to us for credit or choose to be a guarantor, we may need to check your credit reports.
A credit report gives us information about your credit history. Credit reports are provided by credit reporting bodies, who collect and share credit information with credit providers like us, and other service businesses like phone companies.
The Privacy Act limits the information we can give to credit reporting bodies, and that they can give us. The Act also limits how we can use credit reports.
The information we can share with credit reporting bodies include:
Your identity
Type and amount of credit you have – like credit cards, home loans, or personal loans
How much you’ve borrowed
If you’ve made all your repayments
If you’ve committed fraud or another serious credit infringement.
Credit reporting bodies include this information in their credit reports to assist other credit providers assess your credit worthiness.
We can also ask credit reporting bodies to give us your overall credit score, and may use credit information from credit reporting bodies together with other information to arrive at our own scoring of your ability to manage credit.
The credit reporting bodies we use are Equifax Pty Ltd, Experian Australia Credit Services Pty Ltd and illion (formerly known as Dun & Bradstreet). You can download a copy of their privacy policies at:
Equifax - www.equifax.com.au
Experian - www.experian.com.au/credit-services
illion - www.illion.com.au
What do we do with credit information?
We use information from credit reporting bodies to:
Confirm your identity
Assess your credit applications
Assess your ability to manage credit
Manage our relationship with you
Collect overdue payments.
We keep credit information with your other information. You can view this information or ask us to correct it if it’s wrong (see Section 8) or make a complaint to us (see Section 9).
Other rights you have
Direct Marketing – Credit providers like us can ask credit reporting bodies to use your credit information to pre-screen you for direct marketing purposes, but you can tell credit reporting bodies not to (See Section 10).
Preventing identity fraud – If you have been or could be a victim of fraud – for example, if someone else may be using your name to apply for credit – you can ask the credit reporting body not to use or give anyone your credit information.
Our staff are trained in how to keep your information safe and secure. We use secure systems and buildings to hold your information.  We aim to only keep your information for as long as we need it.
We store your hard-copy or electronic records in secure buildings and systems, or using trusted third parties. Here are some of the things we do to protect your information:
Staff training: We train our staff to keep your information safe and secure.
Secure handling and storage: When we send information overseas or use third parties that handle or store data, we put arrangements in place to protect your information.
System security: When you log into our website or apps, we encrypt data sent from your computer to our systems so no one else can access it.
We have firewalls, intrusion detection and virus scanning tools to stop viruses and unauthorised persons from accessing our systems.
When we send your electronic data outside the Group, we use secure networks or encryption.
We use passwords and/or smartcards to stop unauthorised people getting access.
Building security: We use a mix of alarms, cameras, guards and other controls in our buildings to prevent unauthorised access.
Destroying or de-identifying data when no longer required: We aim to keep personal information only for as long as we need it – for example for business or legal reasons. When we no longer need information, we take reasonable steps to destroy or de-identify it.
You can contact us and ask to view your information. For more detailed information, you may need to fill out a request form. If your information isn’t correct or needs updating, let us know straight away.
Can you see what information we have?
You can ask us for a copy of your information, like your transaction history, by visiting a store, going online or calling us. To get a copy of current credit information we have about you, you can visit a store or call us.
For more detailed information, like what we’ve included in your loan file, please contact our Customer Care team using the details in Section 10.
Is there a fee?
No.
How long will it take?
We try to make your information available within 30 days after you ask us for it. Before we give you the information, we’ll need to confirm your identity.
Can we refuse to give you access?
In some cases, we can refuse access or only give you access to certain information. For example, we might not let you see information that is commercially sensitive. If we do this, we’ll write to you explaining our decision.
Updating your information
It’s important that we have your correct details, such as your current home and email addresses and phone number. You can check or update your information at any store, or by going online or calling us (see Section 10).
Can you correct or update your information?
You can ask us to correct or update any information we have (including credit information). See Section 10 for ways to contact us. If we’ve given the information to another party, you can ask us to let them know it’s incorrect. We won’t charge a fee for this.
If the incorrect information was given to us by a credit reporting body, we may need to check with them or the relevant credit provider before we can change it. We’ll try to do this within 30 days. If we can’t, we’ll let you know why it’s taking longer and agree on a new timeframe with you. We’ll also tell you when we’ve corrected the information.
What if we believe the information is correct?
If we don’t think the information needs correcting, we’ll write to let you know why. You can ask us to include a statement with the information that says you believe it’s inaccurate, incomplete, misleading or out of date.
If you have a concern or complaint about your privacy, let us know and we’ll try to fix it. If you’re not satisfied with how we handle your complaint, there are other things you can do.
How can you make a complaint?
We try to get things right the first time – but if we don’t, we’ll do what we can to fix it. If you are concerned about your privacy (including credit information), you can make a complaint and we’ll do our best to sort it out.
To make a complaint, contact one of our staff or customer service teams. We’ll look into the issue and try to fix it straight away. If you’re not satisfied, you can contact our Customer Care team. See Section 10 for contact details.
How do we manage complaints?
We will:
Keep a record of your complaint
Give you a reference number, along with a staff member’s name and contact details if you want to follow it up
Respond to the complaint within a few days if we can, or tell you if we need more time to look into it
Keep you updated on what we’re doing to fix the problem
Give our final response within 45 days (or 90 days for superannuation complaints). If we can’t give you a response in this time, we’ll get in touch to tell you why and work out a new timeframe with you.
Credit information complaints
If your complaint is about your credit information, we may need to check with credit reporting bodies or the credit provider involved. We’ll let you know we’ve received your complaint within seven days. If we can’t sort it out within 30 days, we’ll get in touch to tell you why and work out a new timeframe with you.
What else can you do?
If you’re not satisfied with how we manage your complaint after you’ve been through our internal complaints process, there are free and independent dispute resolution services available to you.
The Australian Financial Complaints Authority can consider most complaints involving financial services providers.
If your complaint is about how we handle your personal information, you can also contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner.
Australian Financial Complaints Authority
GPO Box 3
Melbourne VIC 3001
Free call 1800 931 678
Email info@afca.org.au
Visit www.afca.org.au
Office of the Australian Information Commissioner
GPO Box 5218
Sydney NSW 2001
Phone 1300 363 992
Visit oaic.gov.au
If  you want to update your personal information, or if you have a privacy concern, need more information, or want to update your preferences — help is just a phone call or a few clicks away.
If you are an EU resident and have an enquiry relating to your rights under the GDPR, complete our online feedback form.
To ask a question, access personal information, make a correction or complaint, or get a printed version of this policy:
Step 1: Talk to us
Visit a branch or Business Banking Centre
Call us:
13 17 19 Customer Help Centre
13 7000 Business Support Centre
Online:
After logging into Bankwest Online Banking, go to 'message centre' then click 'Bankmail' to send us a message.
In the Bankwest App, just tap 'Ask us' in the menu to start a secure conversation.
National Relay Service:
TTY/Voice: 133 677
SSR: 1300 555 727
Step 2: Contact Customer Care
If you’re not satisfied, you can contact our Customer Care team.
Customer Care:
Call us on 1800 650 111 between 8am – 8pm local time, 7 days a week
Call us from overseas on +61 8 9449 2840 (international charges apply)
Fax us on 1300 259 233
Complete our online form
Write to us: Manager Customer Care, GPO Box E237, Perth WA 6001
European Union (EU) based General Data Protection Rules (GDPR) legislation has replaced individual country data privacy laws in the EU, giving more rights to EU citizens (who are resident in the EU) as individuals and more obligations to organisations holding their personal information. Personal Information is defined as “any information relating to an identified of identifiable natural person”.
One of the rights is a right to be informed. GDPR requires us to provide more information about how we collect, use, share and store your personal information and your rights as a data subject.
If you are an EU resident and have an enquiry relating to your rights under the GDPR, complete our online feedback form.
These rights are additional to the Group Privacy Policy.
Special Information
The EU GDPR protects your special information. Special information is information about your religion, ethnicity, health or biometrics (for example, your fingerprints). We will only process this type of information, with your consent or where otherwise lawfully permitted.
How long we keep your personal information
We will keep your information for as long as you are a customer of the CBA Group. We aim to keep your information for only as long as we need it. We generally keep your information for up to 7 years after you stop being a customer, but we may keep your information for longer for the purpose of:
fulfilling legal or regulatory obligations
internal research and analytics
responding to a question or complaint or
being unable to delete the data for technical reasons.
How we use your information
We can only collect and use your personal information if we have a valid lawful reason to do so. For the Group, these reasons are:
Contract: We need to process your information in order to fulfil a contract you have with us, or because you have asked us to take specific steps before entering into a contract
Legal obligations: We need to process your information for us to comply with the law (not including contractual obligations)
Consent: You have given clear consent for us to process your personal information for a specific purpose
Legitimate interests: We need to process your information for our legitimate interests or the legitimate interests of a third party. This legitimate interest is overridden where there is a good reason to protect your personal information.
We may use your information to:
confirm your identity
assess your application for a product or service
design, manage, price and provide our products and services
manage our relationship with you
minimise risks and identify or investigate fraud and other illegal activities
contact you, for example, when we need to tell you something important
improve our service to you and your experience with us
comply with laws, and assist government or law enforcement agencies
manage our business
direct marketing.
To find out more about how we use your information, our reasoning and legitimate interests, see Appendix 1 of our Bankwest Privacy Policy (PDF).
The right to be informed how personal information is processed
You have the right to be informed how your personal information is being collected and used. If we require your consent to process your information you can withdraw consent at any time. If you withdraw consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. The right to withdraw only applies when the lawful basis of processing is consent.
The right of access to personal information
If you are an EU resident and have an enquiry relating to your rights under the GDPR, complete our online feedback form.
The right to rectification
You have the right to question any information we have about you that is inaccurate or incomplete. If you do, we will take reasonable steps to check the accuracy and correct it.
The right to erasure
You have the right to ask us to delete your personal information if there is no need for us to keep it. The right to erasure is also known as the right to be forgotten. You can make the request verbally or in writing. There may be legal or other reasons why we need to keep your data and if so we will tell you what these are.
The right to restrict processing
You have the right to ask us to restrict our use of your personal information in some circumstances. We may be able to restrict the use of your data. In this situation we would not use or share your information while it is restricted. This is not an absolute right and only applies in certain circumstances.
The right to data portability
In some circumstances you have the right to request we provide you with a copy of the personal information you have provided to us in a format that can be easily reused.
The right to object
In some circumstances you have the right to object to us processing your personal information. In this case we can continue to hold your data but cannot use it.
Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling
You have rights over automated decisions. You can ask that we do not make our decision based on the automated decisioning alone. You can object to an automated decision and ask that a person reviews it.
The right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority
You have the right to complain to the regulator if you are not happy with the outcome of a complaint.
See the ‘Regulator Contact Details’ section for more information. The individual regulator websites will tell you how to report a concern.
Please note that while any changes you make will be reflected in active user databases instantly or within a reasonable period of time, we may retain all information you submit for backups, archiving, prevention of fraud and abuse, analytics, satisfaction of legal obligations, or where we otherwise reasonably believe that we have a legitimate reason to do so.
You may decline to share certain personal information with us, in which case we may not be able to provide to you some of the features and functionality of the Service.
We will seek parent or guardian consent to collect the personal information of children under 16.
For other European jurisdictions please refer to the European Commission website for details of the relevant data protection authorities.
